<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Givaldo Silva</title>
    <link>https://givaldofrancisco.github.io/portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Givaldo Silva</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://givaldofrancisco.github.io/portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 Forex Profiles</title>
      <link>https://givaldofrancisco.github.io/portfolio/post/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://givaldofrancisco.github.io/portfolio/post/project1/</guid>
      <description>Social media provide a lot of information that can be used to interpret sentiment of the market and it can help to predict the exchange rate, a lot of Twitter profiles attract thousands of followers giving them “Signals”, information about the forex market, these profiles tell them when they should buy, sell, or be neutral. The main goal of this project is to find the best 5 profiles on Twitter regarding forex financial market, the profiles with higher accuracy in their prediction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image classification</title>
      <link>https://givaldofrancisco.github.io/portfolio/post/project4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://givaldofrancisco.github.io/portfolio/post/project4/</guid>
      <description>The objective of this project is to build a machine learning Cat/Dog image classifier. A system to classify whether images contain either a dog or a cat will be implemented. Normalization. Images are created by pixels, each pixel represent a color dot in the imagine, and a digital image are made by number, each number is a pixel and it goes from 0 to 255 divided into 3 colors, as all images have very different tons the number are totally different, when we normalize it, we just put it in the same scale, this makes convergence faster while training the network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting diabetes</title>
      <link>https://givaldofrancisco.github.io/portfolio/post/project3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://givaldofrancisco.github.io/portfolio/post/project3/</guid>
      <description>In this modern time, we have a much easier life than some decades ago, but it also brought some problems, life is so fast that sometimes we don’t have enough time to prepare healthy food, we eat fast food and don’t practice physical activities. Diabetes is one of the most common diseases in our era, affecting millions of people of all ages over the world. Diabetes affects people when they have a high level of blood glucose, this can happen for problems to produce insulin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spam detector</title>
      <link>https://givaldofrancisco.github.io/portfolio/post/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://givaldofrancisco.github.io/portfolio/post/project2/</guid>
      <description>A lot of words, symbols and sometimes numbers are not good for prediction, actually it can have a negative effect in the algorithms, then, we need to clean as much as possible and try to get just the key words that really represent a Spam or ham email. https://github.com/givaldofrancisco/spam_detector/blob/main/Assignment%201%20-%20%20V4.ipynb</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Randon Forest</title>
      <link>https://givaldofrancisco.github.io/portfolio/post/project7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://givaldofrancisco.github.io/portfolio/post/project7/</guid>
      <description>Random forests or random decision forests are an ensemble learning method for classification, regression and other tasks that operate by constructing a multitude of decision trees at training time and outputting the class that is the mode of the classes (classification) or mean/average prediction (regression) of the individual trees.
https://github.com/givaldofrancisco/randon_forest/blob/main/Random-Forest-Python.ipynb</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logistic Regression</title>
      <link>https://givaldofrancisco.github.io/portfolio/post/project6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://givaldofrancisco.github.io/portfolio/post/project6/</guid>
      <description>Logistic regression is a statistical model that in its basic form uses a logistic function to model a binary dependent variable, although many more complex extensions exist. In regression analysis, logistic regression (or logit regression) is estimating the parameters of a logistic model (a form of binary regression).
https://github.com/givaldofrancisco/Logistic_regression/blob/main/Logistic_regression.ipynb</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Linear Regression</title>
      <link>https://givaldofrancisco.github.io/portfolio/post/project5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://givaldofrancisco.github.io/portfolio/post/project5/</guid>
      <description>The relationship between the height of the children and their parents was represented by a mathematical model, which associates the dependent variable with the independent variable, known as the simple linear regression model. Using regression analysis we will take the Housing dataset which contains information about different houses in Boston. This data was originally a part of UCI Machine Learning Repository and has been removed now. We can also access this data from the scikit-learn library.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
